### **TUAN NGUYEN**

E: nganhtuan63@gmail.com - M: 408-417-0710 - Anaheim, CA 92804 linkedin.com/in/nganhtuan63 | github.com/nganhtuan63

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Passionate software developer with 7+ years of experience in web development. Possesses practical knowledge in web app system design and optimization for high-performance. Develops well both backend and frontend components with a focus on reusable code and thoughtful user experience.

- Programming languages: Node.js/Express.js, PHP, HTML/CSS/Javascript
- Databases and Search: MySQL, SQL Server, Redis, Elasticsearch
- Cloud Platform: Amazon Web Services EC2, VPC, ECS, Cloudformation, S3, Lambda, API Gateways, SNS
- Others: Nginx, Docker container, Vagrant, Ansible, RabbitMQ, Varnish, Centos & Ubuntu, Git, Json Web Token
- Open source contribution: GXC-CMS (Github, featured on Softpedia)

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Boost Commerce** - SAAS startup that provides apps and services for e-commerce platforms – Shopify, BigCommerce

### FULL STACK DEVELOPER Sep 2015 - Current

- Designed and developed "Infrastructure as code" for the system with AWS Cloudformation
- Managed and deployed microservices with AWS EC2 Container Service, Elastic Load Balancer, AWS Route53
- Developed REST APIs standard for Product Filter & Search app
- Implemented APIs with AWS Lambda in Node.js and Serverless Framework
- Analyzed and designed ElasticSearch indices to support product filter and search for multiple stores

Hoang Phuc International - Leading trademark in the retail fashion business with more than 110 stores in nation-wide

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER Mar 2015 - Sep 2015

- Improved current e-commerce system for high traffic peak during sale campaigns
- Analyzed and designed Elasticsearch index for flexible product catalog filter

Tuoi Tre Newspaper - The largest daily newspaper in Vietnam

TECHNICAL TEAM LEAD Jan 2013 - Feb 2015

- Implemented and scaled the in-house CMS system for high-traffic 2 million pageviews/day with frequent updated content.
- Improved dynamic publishing workflow and multi-channel publishing
- Managed software development team 10 members

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Mar 2010 - Dec 2012

- Developed first version of in-house Content Management System (CMS) for new publishing strategies
- Developed features & supported deploying Atex CMS for English-version online newspaper

**<u>Pyramid Consulting</u>** - Digital consulting and software development agency serving global-scale clients such as Atlassian, Microsoft, Samsung, Volkswagen, Wal-Mart and others

# **BACKEND WEB DEVELOPER**

Jul 2009 - Oct 2009

- Implemented server-side features for web applications with PHP Zend Framework, MySQL, Memcache

Vinasource - Outsourcing company based out of Seattle, WA and Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

# FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Sep 2008 - Jul 2009

- Developed frontend with HTML/CSS/Javascript from PSD designs for .NET web applications.

# **EDUCATION**

Master's degree in Software Engineering

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

California State University, Fullerton

**Bachelor of Science in Information System** 

Sep 2004 - Sep 2009

Ho Chi Minh City University of Science